A Finding Aid to the Jacques Lipchitz papers and Bruce Bassett papers concerning Jacques Lipchitz, 1910-2001, bulk 1941-2001, in the Archives of American Art AAA.lipcjacq2
Archives of American Art
- Jacques Lipchitz papers, bulk 1941-1999; circa 1910-1999; Series 1; 9.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-10, OV 11-12; Bassett, Bruce W.; Lipchitz, Jacques, 1891-1973
  Among those with whom Lipchtz corresponded regarding commissions are: The Brazilian Embassy ( Prometheus Strangling the Vulture, Ministry of Health and Education, Rio de Janeiro), Vicomte Charles de Noailles ( The Joy of Life) [photocopies of letters from Lipchitz], Jean Devémy (Nôtre Dame de Liesse, Nôtre Dame de Toute Grace at Assy, France), Jane Blaffer Owen (ornamental gates and a cast of Nôtre Dame de Liesse for Philip Johnson's Roofless Church in New Harmony, IN), and the University of Minnesota, Duluth ( Daniel Greysolon, Sieur du Luth). There are numerous letters from Fairmount Park Art Association, Philadelphia Museum of Art, and R. Sturgis Ingersoll regarding multiple projects in Philadelphia; from the Emory Memorial and Robert Taft, Jr. about a memorial to Senator Taft; and from Eloise Spaeth concerning a bust of John F. Kennedy. Also documenting commissions are letters from architects, among them: Eero Saarinen and Associates, Kenneth Franzheim, Philip L. Goodwin, I. M. Pei and Associates, Philip L. Goodwin, and Vincent G. Kling and Associates.
  Art dealers, galleries, and museums were frequent correspondents. They include: The Baltimore Museum of Art, The Bezalel Museum, Brussels Universal and International Exposition, Buchholz Gallery, Cincinnati Art Museum, Corcoran Gallery of Art, Curt Valentin Gallery, Fine Arts Associates (later Otto Gerson Gallery, Inc.), Marlborough-Gerson Gallery, Inc., Museé Bourdelle, Museé National d'Arte Moderne (Paris), Museum of Modern Art (New York), The Museum of Primitive Art, The Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, Philadelphia Museum of Art, Portland Art Museum (Oregon), Rijksmuseum Kröller Muller Otterlo, Stedelijk Museum (Amsterdam), Walker Art Center, Whitney Museum of American Art, and Worcester Art Museum.
  Max N. Benoff, Bernard and Becky Reis, and Alan and Janet Wurtzburger were among the collectors who corresponded with Lipchitz. French artist Pierre Dubaut wrote over an extended period about his collection of Géricault paintings and plans for its eventual disposition. Other individuals who wrote frequently include: critic and writer, Waldemar George; Irene Patai, author of Encounters: The Life of Jacques Lipchitz; and Bert Van Bork, documentary filmmaker and author of Jacques Lipchitz, The Artist at Work; and art historian, Henry R. Hope, a professor active in the College Art Association. The America-Israel Cultural Foundation, Inc. and the International Rescue Committee were also frequent correspondents.
  Of particular note is a lengthy letter (with drafts) to Daniel-Henry Kahnweiler in which Lipchitz explained in detail how the art dealer's writings about Cubist sculpture failed to adequately recognize his contributions to the genre. Extensive correspondence with Rabbi Schneerson includes thoughts about "graven images" in sculpture and contains lengthy religious discussions. Letters from Juan Gris and Josette Gris consist mainly of general news and pleasantries; they do, however, mention Juan Gris's health, and in one letter Gris states he is afraid of working too much and tiring himself out. While basically illegible, Gertrude Stein's letters seem to be short, quick notes about meetings.
  Correspondence with wife Yulla, nephew Gyorgy Hay, and close friends recounts personal and family news, activities, and sometimes touches on future plans. Among these correspondents are: Jenny Courtois, Varian and Annette Fry, Leo Gaspard, R. Sturgis Ingersoll, Gregorio Landau, Juan and Marianne Larrea, Camille Soula, and Joel and Celeste Starrels.
  Eleven small pocket diaries, 1940-1965, contain brief, often sporadic entries noting appointments, events, addresses and phone numbers, notes of expenses, and include some sketches. Among the other writings by Lipchitz are: a notebook containing random notes on sculpture; a list of sculpture destroyed in the 1952 studio fire; short pieces and fragments of writings about sculptors Mary Frank, Natan Rapoport, Auguste Rodin, and William Zorach; a memoir of Amedeo Modigliani; and articles and reflections on contemporary art and the church.
  Catalogue raisonné records concern the compilation and production of The Sculpture of Jacques Lipchitz: A Catalogue Raisonné by Alan G. Wilkinson, sponsored by Marlborough Gallery, Inc.
  Among the financial records are statements of the sculptor's accounts with Buchholz Gallery and Curt Valentin Gallery, and receipts for Lipchitz Collection purchases. Also found are insurance and tax records, as well as receipts for routine professional expenses and miscellaneous personal expenses.
  Artwork consists of a few rough sketches by Lipchitz and several geometric designs by an unidentified artist. Two scrapbooks, 1945-1946, consist of newspaper clippings and a few items from other periodicals that mention Lipchitz or contain reproductions of his work. Volume 2 includes typescripts of an interview and remarks delivered by Lipchitz, both very brief.
  Printed material consists of exhibition catalogs and announcements, articles, press releases, books, programs, and reproductions concerning Lipchitz's exhibitions, sculpture, commissions, and events honoring him. Of particular interest are architectural prints showing sites and project details of several commissions. Also found are a variety of printed items about general art topics.
  Photographs document people, artwork, project sites and models, exhibition installations, events, and places. People include Jacques Lipchitz, family members, and other individuals. Artwork represented is by Lipchitz and other artists. Views of Lipchitz exhibition installations mainly document solo shows. Photographs of events record a variety of occasions, among them: the opening of Lipchitz's studio at Hastings-on-Hudson, NY; a dedication ceremony for Philip Johnson's Roofless Church in New Harmony, IN, with ornamental gates and a sculpture by Lipchitz; and Lipchitz addressing an anatomy class at Albert Einstein Medical College. Among the pictures of places are Lipchitz's studios in Hastings-on-Hudson, NY, and Pietrasanta, Italy, and a view of Picasso's Paris studio.
  Buchholz Gallery (New York, N.Y.).; Cortois, Jenny; Curt Valentin Gallery (New York, N.Y.); Frank, Mary, 1933-; Fry, Annette; Fry, Varian, 1907-1967; Gaspard, Leon, 1882-1964; Hay, Gyorgy; Ingersoll, R. Sturgis (Robert Sturgis), b. 1891; International Business Machines Corporation.; Landau, Gregorio; Larrea, Juan; Larrea, Marianne; Lipchitz, Yulla, 1911-; Marlborough Gallery.; Modigliani, Amedeo, 1884-1920; Noguchi, Isamu, 1904-1988; Rapoport, Nathan, 1911-; Rodin, Auguste, 1840-1917; Soula, Camille, 1888-; Starrels, Celeste; Starrels, Joel; Storm King Art Center; Stott, Deborah; Wilkinson, Alan G., 1941-; Zorach, William, 1887-1966; Artists' studios--Photographs; Diaries; Interviews; Motion pictures (visual works); Photographs; Scrapbooks; Sculptors--New York (State)--New York; Sketches; Sound recordings; Video recordings
  - Biographical Material, 1922-1969; 1.1; 0.1 Linear feet Box 1
    The citation was awarded to Lipchitz by the U.S. Treasury Department, War Finance Committee for "service rendered in the Seventh War Loan May 14-June 29, 1945." Membership cards are from American Society of the French Legion of Honor, Inc., The French Art Theatre, and Museum of Modern Art. Rent receipts are for 54 Rue du Montparnasse, Paris and Lipchitz's New York studio on East 23rd Street; the lease is for a house in Pietrasanta, Italy. A survey prepared for Lipchitz shows the boundaries of his property in Hastings-on-Hudson, NY.
    Arrangement note
    Items are arranged chronologically within each folder. This series has been scanned in its entirety.
    - Address Book, circa 1922-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Addresses, Business Cards, Telephone Numbers, circa 1922-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Biographical Notes, circa 1918-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Citation, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Membership Cards, 1951-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Rent Receipts and Lease, 1922-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Survey of Division Line between Lots 7 and 8 in Block D,", 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1926-1975; 1.2; 4.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-5, OV 11
    This series comprises nearly half of the collection. Approximately 20 percent is in foreign languages, primarily French, with a fair amount in Russian; German, Dutch, Italian, Spanish, Latvian, Hebrew and Yiddish represent the remainder. Correspondence consists largely of incoming letters. Surviving copies of Lipchitz's outgoing letters are mainly drafts, and the earliest ones bear corrections by someone with a better command of English. Drafts of replies often appear on the backs of letters or their accompanying envelopes. Some drafts are written on separate sheets of paper, and multiple letters may appear on a single page.
    Jacques Lipchitz's correspondence illuminates his professional career and personal life, with the substance of many letters combining both. Professional correspondence with collectors, galleries, and museum personnel concerns commissions, exhibition plans, loans, jury service, etc. Architects also corresponded about commissions, and dealers apprised Lipchitz of new inventory that might be of interest for his collection. Art groups, Jewish organizations, and charities wrote to solicit donations of artwork for fundraising events, and issued invitations to speak or be a guest of honor. Scholars contacted Lipchitz about their research requesting information about specific works, items in the Lipchitz Collection, and his opinions about various issues. Also found are fan letters from aspiring artists seeking advice, and from the general public asking for the opportunity to meet Lipchitz and visit his studio. After the 1952 studio fire, many friends and strangers sent letters of condolence and encouragement. Personal correspondence with close friends, wife Yulla, and a nephew recounts personal and family news, activities, and sometimes touches on future plans.
    Additional correspondence is included with the catalogue raisonné documentation (Subseries 5).
    All correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, followed by unidentified, illegible, unsigned letters, and fragments. This series has been scanned in its entirety.
    - 1770 House - Agatstein, Louis G., 1943-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      1770 House
      Ablow, Mr.
      Abrahamsen, David
      Abramson, Samuel H.
      Academia di Belli Arte di Brera
      Acle, Rose
      Adelphi College
      Ades, Josiah
      Adler, Max
      Adler, Stella
      Adolph Studley, Inc., Photographer
      A.D.T. Company, Inc.
      Advertising Women of New York Incorporated
      Agatstein, Louis G.
    - Albert Einstein Commemorative Dinner - Amendola, Robert, 1944-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Albert Einstein Commemorative Dinner
      Albert Loeb Gallery
      Albright Art Gallery/Albright-Knox Art Gallery
      Alexander, Fritz W., II
      Al Gongol, Gregory
      Al Gongol, Sandy
      Alliance in Art
      Alpert, Max
      Altman, Harold, Anita, and Evan
      Ambellan, Harold
      Amendola, Robert
    - America-Israel Cultural Foundation, Inc., 1960-1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Artist - American Jewish Tercentenary Committee, 1949-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      American Artist
      American Artists Professional League
      American Broadcasting Company (ABC)
      American Center for Students and Artists
      American Committee for Shaare Zedek Hospital in Jerusalem, Inc.
      American Craftsmen's Council
      American Federation of Arts
      American Friends of the Hebrew University
      American Fund for Israel Institutions
      American Institute of Architects
      American International Music Fund, Inc.
      American-Israel World's Fair Corporation
      American Jewish Committee
      American Jewish Congress
      American Jewish Tercentenary Committee
    - American Lithuanian Foundation, Inc. - L'Architecture d'Aujourd'Hui, 1948-1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      American Lithuanian Foundation, Inc.
      American Memorial to Six Million Jews of Europe, Inc.
      American Society for Technion, Israel Institute of Technology, Inc., Tenafly (NJ) Chapter Women's Division
      American Society of the French Legion of Honor, Inc.
      American University
      Ames, Winslow
      Amherst College
      Amis de Nogent
      Amis de Soutine
      Amkreutz, Agnes
      Amman, Max E.
      Amoretti, Enrico
      Amsterdam, Burgomaster of
      André Emmerich Gallery
      Anne Landsman Interior Designer
      Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith
      Antioch College
      Antman, Joe
      Antwerp, City of
      A.P.F., Inc.
      Archaeological Artifacts and Antiques, Inc.
      Architectural Forum
      Architectural League of New York
      L'Architecture d'Aujourd'Hui
    - Archives of American Art - Artists Overseas Aid Association, 1945-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Archives of American Art
      Archivio Storico d'Arte Contemporanea della Biennale
      Arfa, Jennie Nusskern
      Arnason, H. H.
      Arrighini, Nicola
      Arroso
      Art Association of Indianapolis, Indiana/The John Herron Art Institute
      Art Digest
      Art Directors' Club, Inc.
      Art Gallery of Toronto
      Artibus Asiae
      Art in America
      Art Institute of Chicago
      Art Institute of Chicago, Society for Contemporary Art
      Art League of Houston
      Art of This Century
      Art Squad, Inc.
      Artistenblad
      Artist's Committee for Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee
      Artists Equity Association, Chicago Chapter
      Artists Equity Association, Philadelphia Chapter
      Artists for SEDF (Scholarship, Education and Defense Fund for Racial Equality, Inc.)
      Artists Overseas Aid Association
    - Arts Club of Chicago - Balestrant, Stephen, 1947-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Arts Club of Chicago
      Arts Council of Great Britain
      Ascher
      Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies
      Association Française d'Action Artistique
      Association Française Contre la Peine de Mort
      Aström, Paul
      Atlanta Art Association
      Attias, Elaine
      Audubon Artists, Inc.
      Avant-Garde
      Avedon, Richard
      Avnet, Lester
      Baal-Teshuva, Jacob
      Bacal, Jacob
      Baker, Bernard
      Balestrant, Stephen
    - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1953-1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Band, Max - Bennington College, 1944-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Band, Max
      Bank of Israel
      Bard College
      Barnard College Club of Monmouth County, New Jersey
      Barnes Foundation
      Barr, Alfred H. and Margaret
      Barran, Fritz
      Barry, Margaret
      Bass, Basil N.
      Bassett, Bruce
      Bastone, James
      Bat-Yam Institute for Plastic Art
      Bean, Marshall E.
      Raymond R. Beatty, Inc.
      Beaudin, Nicolas
      Becker, Marvin C.
      Belgium, Ministere de l'Education Nationale et de la Culture
      Bellak, Richard F.
      Bennington College
    - Benoff, Max N. (Mac), Miki, and Robin, 1955-1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Benson Emmanuel M. and Gertrude - Bet Ami, 1950-1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Benson, Emmanuel M. and Gertrude
      Bentein, Mrs.
      Ben-Yakov, Rudi
      Berger, Jason
      Berger, S. A.
      Berk, Lane Kolker
      Berkowitz, Allan A.
      Berman, Gizel
      Berman, L.
      Berman, Mr.
      Berman, Mrs.
      Bernal Antiquary
      Bernard, Eunice
      Bernheimer's Antique Arts
      Bertha Schaeffer Gallery
      Berthold, Gertrude
      Bertrand Russell Peace Foundation
      Berus, Hélène
      Bet Ami
    - Bezalel National Museum (Israel), 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Biberfield, J. - Biennale di Venezia, 1950-1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Biberfeld, J.
      Biddle, George
      Bienale d'Arte Triveneta
      Biennale di Venezia
    - Bing, Anna, 1956-1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bitterman, Eleanor - Brandeis Institute, 1945-1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Bitterman, Eleanor
      Blanke
      Bleackley, Carol
      Bloch, Virginia R.
      Blue Moon Gallery
      Blum, Hélène
      Boar's Head
      Bob, Emil
      Bode, Arnold and Marilouise
      Bollinger, Hans
      Bollt, Robert
      Bookstaber, Henry
      Booth, Winkie
      Borenstein, S.
      Borowski, Elie
      Boston Arts Festival
      Boston University
      Braat, L.P.J.
      Brandeis Institute
    - Brandeis University - Brandeis University National Women's Committee, Philadelphia Chapter, 1955-1964 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Oversized material housed in OV 11, F1
      Brandeis University
      Brandeis University National Women's Committee, Philadelphia Chapter
    - Brazilian Embassy, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Brein, Arnold - Brody, Mrs., 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Brein, Arnold
      Brent, P.
      Brera Produzione Cinematografica
      Bright, David E.
      Broadcast Recording Service
      Brodie, Gandy
      Brody, Mrs.
    - Brooklyn Museum - Bruno Tartaglia Transporti Internazionali, 1955-1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Brooklyn Museum
      Brooklyn Society of Artists, Inc.
      Brooks, Peggy Jones
      Brown, Edward
      Brown, John P.
      Brown, Nell
      Browne, Ken
      Brownstone, Lucien and Ethel
      Bruno Tartaglia Transporti Internazionali
    - Brussels Universal and International Exposition 1958, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bryson, Clayton J. - Bugnard, Claude, 1942-1963 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Bryson, Clayton J.
      Buchholz Gallery
      Buessow, Marguerite
      Bugnard, Claude
    - Bugnard, Louis, 1952-1964 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Bureau of Jewish Education - Carlebach Gallery, 1943-1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Bureau of Jewish Education
      Burke, Phyllis Ann
      Burke Literary Representative (Burke, Shirley)
      Burstein, Barney
      Bush, Mr.
      Byron Gallery, Inc.
      Cabell, Ellen R.
      Calder, Alexander
      Calfee, William H.
      Callery, Mary
      Camemann, Schuyler
      Campbell, Robert
      Canaday, John and Katherine
      Canarsie High School (Brooklyn, NY)
      Carlebach Gallery
    - Carleton College, 1954-1964 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Carnegie Institute - Century Association, 1944-1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Carnegie Institute
      Carrier, Raffaele
      Carruth, Frank, III
      Carton, Norman
      Casa Editrice Libraria Ulrico Hoepli
      Casey, Mrs. Robert B.
      Catherwood Foundation
      Cato, Robert
      Caywood, Ann
      C. Dirkan Kelekian Ancient Arts
      Cella, Nicole
      Center for Cross-Cultural Communication
      Century Association
    - Chandler, Buff - Ciardi, John, 1945-1967 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Chandler, Buff
      Chanin, A.
      Chappaqua P.T.A. (NY)
      Chareau, Dollie
      Charles E. Slatkin, Inc. Galleries
      Charles H. Voorheees and Co., Inc.
      Chase, Prof.
      Cherne, Leo
      Children's Day Nurseries in Israel
      Christian Action
      Ciardi, John
    - Cincinnati Art Museum, 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - City Art Museum of St. Louis - Coluccini Giuliano Artigiano Formatore, 1950-1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      City Art Museum of St. Louis
      Clemson College
      Cleveland Center for the Arts
      Cleveland Museum of Art
      Clifford, Henry
      Coder Taylor Associates, Architects, Engineers, Planners
      Cogniat, Raymond
      Cohen, Alma
      Cohen, Mortimer J.
      Cohen, Samuel M.
      Cohen, Mr.
      Colgate University
      College Art Association
      Colp, Ralph
      Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc. (CBS)
      Coluccini Giuliano Artigiano Formatore
    - Columbia University, 1949-1969 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Comay, Michael and Joan - Contact, 1952-1967 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Comay, Michael and Joan
      Comité du Monument de la Légion d'Honneur et de la Colonne de la Grande Armée
      Conference on the Status of Soviet Jews
      Congregation Beth-El (Philadelphia)
      Congregation B'nai Jeshurun (New York)
      Congregation Ohabai Sholom (Nashville)
      Congregation Rodef Sholom (Waco, TX)
      Congregation Shaare Zedek (Southfield, MI)
      Congrés pour la Liberté de la Culture
      Congress for Jewish Culture
      Consolidated Edison
      Contact
    - Contemporary Arts Association of Houston, Inc. - Coordinating Council of French Relief Societies, Inc., 1943-1962 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Contemporary Arts Association of Houston, Inc.
      Cook, Mr.
      Cook, Edith Valet
      Coordinating Council of French Relief Societies, Inc.
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1951-1969 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Coreos, Josie - Costa, Ernest, 1952-1962 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Coreos, Josie
      Cornell Forum
      Cornell University
      Cornell University, Andrew Dickson White Museum of Art
      Corning Museum of Glass
      Costa, Ernest
    - Courtois, Jenny, 1945-1955 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Couturier, Marie-Alain - Cowles, Fleur, 1948-1961 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Couturier, Marie-Alain
      Couzijn, W.
      Cowles, Fleur
    - Cowles, John and Betty, 1955-1963 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Creative Arts Gallery - Cunliffe, Marcus, Mitzi, and Antonia, 1945-1967 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Creative Arts Gallery
      Crockwell, Douglass
      Cross, Christopher
      Crown Publishers, Inc.
      Cunliffe, Marcus, Mitzi, and Antonia
    - Curt Valentin Gallery, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Dade, Philip L. - Darsky, Mr., 1952-1967 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      Dade, Philip L.
      Dagblad de Tijd
      Dallek, Godfrey H.
      Dalsace, Jean and Annie
      Dalsheimer, Helen M.
      Dambek, Blanche
      Daniel, Eve
      Darsky, Mr.
    - Davidson, Abraham A. - De Noto, Joseph, 1945-1967 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Davidson, Abraham A.
      Davis, A. R.
      Davis, Richard S. and Phyllis
      Day, Faith
      D Contemporary Paintings
      Déchelette
      de Creeft, José
      De Dublé, Mercedes García Huidobro
      de Hauke, C.
      de Henriquez, Alfonso and Marta
      Delbanco, Kurt
      de Menil
      Democratic Party, Artists and Performers National Committee
      de Noailles, Marie Laure
      De Noto, Joseph
    - DePauw University - Deutsch, Armand S., 1947-1968 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      DePauw University
      de Ruyter, O.
      de Sola Pool, D.
      Deutsch, Armand S.
    - Devémy, Jean, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Dickinson, Edwin - Drummond, Janet Hickey, 1947-1970 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      Dickinson, Edwin
      Dickson, Louise M.
      Dietrich, Volkmar
      Dilia Czechoslovak Theatrical and Literary Agency
      Direction Générale des Arts et des Lettres
      Dissent
      Djambatan, Ltd.
      Dobkin, Eliahu
      Documenta
      Dominique, M. C.
      Donohoe, Miss
      Dorekens, Guy
      Doren, Daniel
      Doris Weiner Gallery
      Dorra, Henry
      Dowling, Robert W.
      Downtown Gallery
      Dreyfuss, Henry
      Drummond, Janet Hickey
    - Dubaut, Pierre, 1950-1966; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 52-53)
    - Dubuffet, Jean - Edward MacDowell Association, Inc., 1949-1968 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      Dubuffet, Jean
      Duda, Martha
      Duluth Herald and Duluth News-Tribune
      Duvkin, Elijah
      East Cleveland Museum Galleries
      Ecuador, Republic of
      Edelstein, Mr. and Mrs. Eugene
      Éditions d'Art Albert Skira
      Éditions des Trois Collines
      Editions Mozaika
      Edward MacDowell Association, Inc.
    - Eero Saarinen and Associates, 1952-1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Eitner, Lorenz - Emery, George L., 1949-1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)